<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Welcome on This Adds Up</title><link>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/</link><description>Recent content in Welcome on This Adds Up</description><generator>Hugo -- 0.147.6</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 22:48:53 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How does 5g home internet work? exploring t-mobile and verizon</title><link>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-5g-home-internet-work/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 22:48:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-5g-home-internet-work/</guid><description>Learn how 5G home internet works with T-Mobile and Verizon, offering faster speeds and better connections for all your devices.</description><content:encoded>&lt;p>5G home internet is super fast and helps us connect to the internet better than ever! It’s like having a speedy highway for your devices. T-Mobile and Verizon are two companies that use 5G to make sure you can download videos, play games, and chat online quickly. With 5G, many devices can connect at once, even in busy places. This means you can enjoy smooth streaming and gaming without waiting. It&amp;rsquo;s a big step up from 4G, letting us use cool new technologies like smart cars and robots. So, 5G is not just fast; it helps build a smarter world!&lt;/p>
</content:encoded></item><item><title>What is blockchain? simple explanation for kids</title><link>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/what-is-blockchain-in-simple-words/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 22:48:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/what-is-blockchain-in-simple-words/</guid><description>Learn what blockchain is in simple words and how it helps keep digital information safe and secure.</description><content:encoded>&lt;p>Blockchain is like a special digital notebook that keeps track of information in a really safe way. Imagine a chain made of blocks, where each block has important details and is connected to the one before it. This makes it hard to change anything once it&amp;rsquo;s written down! It was created to help people use digital money, like Bitcoin, without needing a bank. Many businesses are also looking at blockchain to keep their information safe. So, blockchain helps everyone keep track of things in a super secure way!&lt;/p>
</content:encoded></item><item><title>How does student loan interest work? a simple guide for kids</title><link>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-student-loan-interest-work/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 22:48:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-student-loan-interest-work/</guid><description>Learn how student loan interest works, including interest rates and repayment options for students in different countries.</description><content:encoded>&lt;p>Student loans help you pay for school, like college or university. When you borrow money, you usually have to pay it back later. The money you pay extra is called interest. Interest rates are how much extra money you pay on top of what you borrowed. Some countries have special rules for student loans, like lower interest rates or no interest while you study. In places like Australia and New Zealand, they have different ways to help students pay back their loans when they start working. Understanding how interest works can help you plan for your future!&lt;/p>
</content:encoded></item><item><title>How does voip work? understanding voice calls over the internet</title><link>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-voip-work/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 22:48:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-voip-work/</guid><description>Learn how VoIP works and how voice calls are made over the Internet with this fun and simple explanation.</description><content:encoded>&lt;p>Have you ever wondered how you can talk to someone over the Internet? That’s where VoIP comes in! VoIP stands for Voice over Internet Protocol. It helps us make phone calls using the Internet instead of regular phone lines. When you talk, your voice turns into tiny digital packets that travel through the web to reach the other person. You can use special VoIP phones or even regular phones with a little help. VoIP is super cool because it makes it easier to call people anywhere, especially with apps like Skype and Google Voice. So next time you chat online, you’ll know how it works!&lt;/p>
</content:encoded></item><item><title>Understanding how loan interest works: a kid's guide</title><link>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-loan-interest-work/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 22:48:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-loan-interest-work/</guid><description>Learn how loan interest works and how it affects borrowing and saving money in this fun, kid-friendly guide.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Have you ever borrowed money from a bank? When you do, you have to pay back a little extra called interest. This is the bank&rsquo;s way of making money from lending to you. So, if you borrow $100, you might end up paying back $110. That extra $10 is the interest! But guess what? If you save money in the bank, you can earn interest too! The bank pays you a bit more than what you put in. So, whether you&rsquo;re borrowing or saving, understanding how loan interest works is super important!</p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>How do ip addresses work? a simple guide for kids</title><link>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-do-ip-addresses-work/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 22:48:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-do-ip-addresses-work/</guid><description>Learn how IP addresses work and why they are essential for devices to communicate on the internet.</description><content:encoded>&lt;p>IP addresses are like phone numbers for computers! Every device that connects to the internet gets a special number, called an IP address, to help it communicate. There are two types: IPv4 and IPv6. IPv4 is the older version with shorter numbers, while IPv6 is newer and has longer numbers to give more devices their own addresses. Just like how your home address helps people find you, an IP address helps computers find each other on the internet. Isn’t that cool?&lt;/p>
</content:encoded></item><item><title>How does a cash advance work on a credit card?</title><link>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-a-cash-advance-work-on-a-credit-card/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 22:48:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-a-cash-advance-work-on-a-credit-card/</guid><description>Learn how a cash advance works on a credit card and what you need to know before using this option.</description><content:encoded>&lt;p>Have you ever wondered how a cash advance works on a credit card? It’s like getting money from your card when you need it! When you use a cash advance, you can take out cash right away, but remember, you will need to pay it back later. Plus, there might be extra fees and interest. So, it’s important to use it wisely. Cash advances can be helpful in emergencies, but it’s best to save your money for later. Always ask an adult if you&amp;rsquo;re unsure about using a cash advance!&lt;/p>
</content:encoded></item><item><title>How does fiber optic internet work? a simple guide</title><link>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-fiber-optic-internet-work/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 22:48:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-fiber-optic-internet-work/</guid><description>Discover how fiber optic internet works and why it&amp;#39;s super fast and reliable for your online activities.</description><content:encoded>&lt;p>Have you ever wondered how fiber optic internet works? It uses tiny glass strands to send light signals super fast! Instead of using wires, fiber optics send information as light. This means you can watch videos and play games without any lag. It’s really cool because it can send lots of information over long distances without losing speed. Many companies use fiber optics for phones, internet, and TV. So, next time you go online, remember that light is zooming through those fibers to help you connect!&lt;/p>
</content:encoded></item><item><title>How does a portable hotspot work? discover the magic of mobile wi-fi!</title><link>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-a-portable-hotspot-work/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 22:48:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-a-portable-hotspot-work/</guid><description>Learn how a portable hotspot works and discover the amazing world of mobile Wi-Fi and wireless hotspots!</description><content:encoded>&lt;p>Have you ever wanted to use the Internet on your tablet or phone, but there was no Wi-Fi around? That&amp;rsquo;s where a portable hotspot comes in! A portable hotspot is a special device that lets you connect to the Internet anywhere. It works by using a mobile data plan, just like your cell phone. You can share this Internet connection with other devices, like laptops or gaming consoles. Some places, like coffee shops or libraries, also have public hotspots that everyone can use. So, whether you’re at home or on the go, portable Wi-Fi helps keep you connected!&lt;/p>
</content:encoded></item><item><title>How do credit card miles work? a fun guide for kids!</title><link>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-miles-work-on-credit-card/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 22:48:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-miles-work-on-credit-card/</guid><description>Learn how credit card miles work, including how to earn airline miles and points from American Express and Chase in this fun guide.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Have you ever heard of credit card miles? They are special rewards that you earn when you use your credit card to buy things. Just like collecting stickers or points, every time you spend money, you can get miles! These miles can help you travel or get cool stuff. Different cards, like American Express or Chase, have their own ways of giving you these points. So, when you use your card, you&rsquo;re not just buying; you&rsquo;re also collecting miles that can take you on fun adventures!</p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>How does interest work? understanding interest rates made easy!</title><link>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-interest-work/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 22:48:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-interest-work/</guid><description>Learn how interest works and how interest rates affect borrowing and saving in simple terms for kids!</description><content:encoded>&lt;p>Have you ever borrowed money or saved some in a bank? That&amp;rsquo;s where interest comes in! Interest is the extra money you pay back when you borrow or the extra money you earn when you save. If you take a loan from a bank, you pay back more than you borrowed. But if you save money, the bank pays you extra as interest for letting them use your money. So, interest is like a reward for saving or a cost for borrowing. Pretty cool, right?&lt;/p>
</content:encoded></item><item><title>How does inflation work? understanding price changes!</title><link>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-inflation-work/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 22:48:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-inflation-work/</guid><description>Learn how inflation works and why it affects the prices of goods and services in our economy.</description><content:encoded>&lt;p>Inflation is when prices go up, making everything cost more money. Imagine if your favorite candy used to cost $1, but now it costs $1.10. That’s inflation! It happens for different reasons, like when more people want to buy things or when supplies are low. Sometimes, inflation can be good because it helps businesses grow and creates jobs. But too much inflation can be bad, making it hard for people to buy what they need. Central banks, like the ones that control money, try to keep inflation low and steady so that the economy stays healthy!&lt;/p>
</content:encoded></item><item><title>How does cash back work? understanding cash back credit cards</title><link>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-cash-back-work/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 22:48:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-cash-back-work/</guid><description>Learn how cash back works on credit cards and discover how you can earn money back on your purchases with cash back credit cards.</description><content:encoded>&lt;p>Have you ever heard of cash back? It’s a cool way to earn money back when you use a credit card to buy things! When you use a cash back card, a little bit of the money you spend comes back to you. This could be a percentage of your purchases, like 1% or even 5%. So, if you buy a toy for $100 and your card gives you 1% cash back, you get $1 back! Isn’t that fun? Just remember, you have to pay off your credit card bill later. This is how cash back credit cards work to help you earn money while you shop!&lt;/p>
</content:encoded></item><item><title>How does compound interest work? a fun guide!</title><link>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-compound-interest-work/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 22:48:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-compound-interest-work/</guid><description>Discover how compound interest works and why it’s important for saving money in this fun and easy guide!</description><content:encoded>&lt;p>Have you ever heard of compound interest? It’s like magic for your money! When you save money, you earn interest, which is a little extra cash. With compound interest, you earn interest on your original amount and also on the interest you&amp;rsquo;ve already earned. This means your money can grow faster! For example, if you save $100 and earn 10% interest, after one year, you’ll have $110. But in the next year, you earn interest on $110, not just $100! That’s why it’s super important to understand how compound interest works. It can help you save up for cool things in the future!&lt;/p>
</content:encoded></item><item><title>How does wi-fi work? discover wireless internet magic!</title><link>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-wifi-work/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 22:48:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-wifi-work/</guid><description>Learn how Wi-Fi works and discover the magic of wireless internet, including how a Wi-Fi router connects your devices to the web!</description><content:encoded>&lt;p>Have you ever wondered how Wi-Fi works? It’s like magic that helps your devices talk to each other without any wires! Wi-Fi uses special radio waves to send data between your phone, tablet, or computer and the internet. When you connect to Wi-Fi at home or in a cafe, a small box called a router helps connect everything. This router sends and receives signals, so you can watch videos or play games online. Just remember, walls and furniture can block the signal, so it works best when you’re close to the router. Isn’t that cool?&lt;/p>
</content:encoded></item><item><title>How does a secured credit card work? easy guide for kids!</title><link>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-a-secured-credit-card-work/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 22:48:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-a-secured-credit-card-work/</guid><description>Learn how a secured credit card works and how it can help you build your credit in a fun and easy way!</description><content:encoded>&lt;p>A secured credit card is a special type of credit card that helps people build their credit. To get one, you pay money upfront, which is like a deposit. This money is used as your credit limit. When you buy something with the card, you are borrowing money, but you need to pay it back later. Using a secured credit card responsibly can help you improve your credit score. It’s a great way to learn about managing money and making smart choices!&lt;/p>
</content:encoded></item><item><title>How do balance transfers work? a kid-friendly guide</title><link>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-do-balance-transfers-work/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 22:48:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-do-balance-transfers-work/</guid><description>Learn how balance transfers work and how you can save money by moving your credit card debt to a card with lower interest rates.</description><content:encoded>&lt;p>A balance transfer is when you move money you owe from one credit card to another. This can help you save money because some credit cards offer low or even 0% interest rates for a while. It’s like getting a special deal! When you switch your balance, the new bank often wants you as a customer, so they give you these cool perks. Just remember, you usually have to pay off the lowest interest first. And you can&amp;rsquo;t move your balance between cards from the same bank. Easy peasy!&lt;/p>
</content:encoded></item><item><title>How does a wifi extender work? discover the magic of boosting your internet!</title><link>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/wifi-extender-how-does-it-work/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 22:48:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/wifi-extender-how-does-it-work/</guid><description>Learn how a WiFi extender works to boost your internet signal and reach every corner of your home!</description><content:encoded>&lt;p>Have you ever wanted to use the internet in a spot where the signal is weak? That’s where a WiFi extender comes in! A WiFi extender picks up the internet signal from your router and sends it out again to cover more area. Think of it like a loudspeaker that makes your favorite song heard in every corner of your house! It helps your devices connect to the internet even if they are far away from the router. So, if you want to play games or watch videos in the backyard, a WiFi extender can help make that happen!&lt;/p>
</content:encoded></item><item><title>How does the internet work? exploring the basics</title><link>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-the-internet-work/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 22:48:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-the-internet-work/</guid><description>Learn how the Internet works and explore the basics of this amazing network that connects computers and people worldwide.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Have you ever wondered how the Internet works? It&rsquo;s like a giant web connecting computers all over the world! The Internet lets us share information, play games, and talk to friends, no matter where they are. It started a long time ago with researchers who wanted to help computers talk to each other. Now, we can send emails, watch videos, and even shop online. There are no single rules for the Internet, but many people help keep it running smoothly. So, the next time you go online, remember that it&rsquo;s a big, amazing network that connects us all!</p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Understanding apr: how does it work on credit cards?</title><link>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-apr-work/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 22:48:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-apr-work/</guid><description>Learn how APR works on credit cards and why understanding the annual percentage rate is important for managing your money wisely.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Have you ever wondered what APR means? APR stands for Annual Percentage Rate. It&rsquo;s like a big number that shows how much extra money you pay when you borrow money using a credit card. If you don&rsquo;t pay back the money right away, the bank charges you a little bit more each month. This extra money adds up over a year. Knowing how APR works helps you understand how to use credit cards wisely and avoid paying too much. So, next time you hear about APR, you&rsquo;ll know it&rsquo;s all about the cost of borrowing money!</p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>How does starlink work? exploring satellite internet!</title><link>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-starlink-work/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 22:47:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-starlink-work/</guid><description>Discover how Starlink works and learn about satellite internet and how it connects us from space!</description><content:encoded>&lt;p>Starlink is a special kind of Internet that comes from satellites high in the sky. These satellites send signals to our homes, allowing us to browse the web and play games. Unlike normal Internet, which uses cables, Starlink uses satellites that orbit the Earth. This means you can get fast Internet even in places where cables can’t reach! Starlink is making Internet access easier for everyone, especially in remote areas. So, next time you go online, remember that some of that magic comes from space!&lt;/p>
</content:encoded></item><item><title>How does a microwave work? fun facts about microwave cooking!</title><link>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-a-microwave-work/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 22:47:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-a-microwave-work/</guid><description>Learn how does a microwave work and discover the science behind microwave cooking and heating food quickly.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Have you ever wondered how a microwave heats your food so quickly? A microwave oven uses special waves to make water molecules in your food move around, which creates heat. This is called dielectric heating! The first microwave was invented a long time ago, and now we use them every day to warm up leftovers and cook meals. They are super handy for making things like popcorn or melting chocolate. But be careful! Microwaves don&rsquo;t brown food like a stove does. Next time you use a microwave, you&rsquo;ll know the science behind it!</p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>How does a credit card work? a simple guide for kids</title><link>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-a-credit-card-work/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 22:47:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-a-credit-card-work/</guid><description>Learn how does a credit card work, including how credit card interest works and how to manage payments effectively.</description><content:encoded>&lt;p>Have you ever wondered how credit cards work? A credit card lets you buy things now and pay for them later. When you use one, the bank pays the store for you, and then you owe the bank money. If you don’t pay it all back by the due date, you might have to pay extra money called interest. This is how credit card interest works! Just remember, it’s important to pay your credit card bill on time so you don’t have to pay more. Using a credit card can be helpful, but you have to be careful with it!&lt;/p>
</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>