<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Posts on This Adds Up</title><link>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on This Adds Up</description><generator>Hugo -- 0.147.6</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 23:33:40 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How 5g home internet works</title><link>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-5g-home-internet-work/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 23:33:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-5g-home-internet-work/</guid><description>Learn how 5G home internet works and its impact on companies like T-Mobile and Verizon.</description><content:encoded>&lt;p>5G is the fifth generation of cellular network technology. It is faster than 4G and can connect more devices at once. 5G has low delays, which helps with real-time communication. This technology can improve services like home internet. Companies like T-Mobile and Verizon offer 5G home internet. They use special antennas to send and receive signals. This allows people to get internet even in crowded areas. Although 5G has many benefits, it also needs a lot of investment to build the networks. 5G is important for new technologies and can help in many fields like healthcare and transportation.&lt;/p>
</content:encoded></item><item><title>What is blockchain in simple words</title><link>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/what-is-blockchain-in-simple-words/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 23:33:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/what-is-blockchain-in-simple-words/</guid><description>Learn what blockchain is in simple words and how it works as a secure digital record-keeping system.</description><content:encoded>&lt;p>Blockchain is a type of digital record-keeping. It stores information in blocks that are connected together in a chain. Each block has a link to the one before it, making it hard to change any information. This system helps keep records safe and secure. Blockchain was first used for Bitcoin, a type of digital money, but it can also be used for other things. Some businesses are looking at private blockchains to keep their data secure. Overall, blockchain is a way to record transactions without needing a central authority.&lt;/p>
</content:encoded></item><item><title>How student loan interest works</title><link>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-student-loan-interest-work/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 23:33:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-student-loan-interest-work/</guid><description>Learn how student loan interest works, including repayment rules and interest rates in different countries.</description><content:encoded>&lt;p>Student loans help pay for college costs like tuition and books. They usually have lower interest rates than other loans. Some loans let students wait to pay until they finish school. In Australia, a special program called HECS-HELP helps students repay loans based on their income after they graduate. In New Zealand, students do not pay interest while living there. They start paying back loans when they earn above a certain amount. Each country has different rules for student loans.&lt;/p>
</content:encoded></item><item><title>How voip works: a simple guide</title><link>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-voip-work/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 23:33:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-voip-work/</guid><description>Learn how VoIP works to make voice calls over the Internet using simple technology.</description><content:encoded>&lt;p>VoIP stands for Voice over Internet Protocol. It lets people make voice calls using the Internet instead of regular phone lines. VoIP changes voice sounds into data packets that travel over the Internet. You can use special VoIP phones or regular phones with adapters to connect to the Internet. VoIP also works with mobile phones through networks like 4G and 5G. This technology is used in apps like Skype and Google Voice. VoIP calls are similar to traditional phone calls, but they use digital signals and special codes to send sound clearly.&lt;/p>
</content:encoded></item><item><title>How loan interest works</title><link>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-loan-interest-work/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 23:33:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-loan-interest-work/</guid><description>Learn how loan interest works and how it affects borrowing and saving money.</description><content:encoded>&lt;p>Loan interest is the extra money you pay when you borrow money from a bank. When you take out a loan, you agree to pay back the amount you borrowed plus interest. This interest is usually a percentage of the loan amount. For example, if you borrow $100, you might pay back $110. Interest can also work the other way. When you save money in a bank, you earn interest too. The bank pays you extra money for keeping your savings there. In both cases, interest is a way for banks to make money and for people to earn money on their savings.&lt;/p>
</content:encoded></item><item><title>How do ip addresses work?</title><link>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-do-ip-addresses-work/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 23:33:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-do-ip-addresses-work/</guid><description>Learn how IP addresses work and their role in internet communication.</description><content:encoded>&lt;p>An IP address is a number that identifies a device on the internet. It helps devices communicate with each other. There are two main types of IP addresses: IPv4 and IPv6. IPv4 is older and uses 32 bits, while IPv6 is newer and uses 128 bits. This allows for many more addresses since the internet has grown so much. IP addresses are managed by a group called IANA and passed to local internet providers. Some addresses are kept for private use and do not appear on the internet.&lt;/p>
</content:encoded></item><item><title>How a cash advance works on a credit card</title><link>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-a-cash-advance-work-on-a-credit-card/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 23:33:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-a-cash-advance-work-on-a-credit-card/</guid><description>Learn how a cash advance works on a credit card, including costs and repayment.</description><content:encoded>&lt;p>A cash advance on a credit card lets you borrow money using your card. You can take out cash from an ATM or bank. This money is part of your credit limit and you must pay it back. Cash advances often have higher fees and interest rates than regular purchases. It is important to understand these costs before using a cash advance. Make sure you know how much you will owe and when to pay it back.&lt;/p>
</content:encoded></item><item><title>How fiber optic internet works</title><link>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-fiber-optic-internet-work/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 23:33:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-fiber-optic-internet-work/</guid><description>Learn how fiber optic internet works and why it is faster and more reliable than traditional methods.</description><content:encoded>&lt;p>Fiber optic internet sends information using light through thin glass or plastic cables called optical fibers. This method is better than traditional wires for long distances and high speeds. The light carries data like voice, video, and internet signals. Fiber optics have changed how we communicate since they were first developed in the 1970s. They are now commonly used by many internet and phone companies because they are faster and more reliable than older methods. The use of fiber optics has helped improve communication around the world.&lt;/p>
</content:encoded></item><item><title>How portable hotspots work: a simple guide</title><link>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-a-portable-hotspot-work/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 23:32:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-a-portable-hotspot-work/</guid><description>Learn how portable hotspots work and how they provide Internet access using Wi-Fi technology.</description><content:encoded>&lt;p>A portable hotspot is a device that allows you to connect to the Internet using Wi-Fi. It works by using a mobile network to provide Internet access to other devices, like smartphones or laptops. You can set up a portable hotspot on some smartphones or tablets if they have a data plan. Public hotspots are found in places like coffee shops and libraries, allowing many people to access the Internet. Some libraries lend portable hotspots to help people who do not have Internet at home. This helps more people connect to online services.&lt;/p>
</content:encoded></item><item><title>How credit card miles work</title><link>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-miles-work-on-credit-card/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 23:32:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-miles-work-on-credit-card/</guid><description>Learn how credit card miles work and how to earn points with cards like American Express and Chase.</description><content:encoded>&lt;p>Credit card miles are part of loyalty programs that reward you for spending. When you use a credit card for purchases, you earn points or miles. These points can be used for travel, like flights or hotel stays. Different credit cards, like American Express and Chase, have their own ways to earn and use these points. You can also get a loyalty card to track your points. This card may look like a credit card and helps you show that you are part of the program. Knowing how these systems work can help you get more rewards for your spending.&lt;/p>
</content:encoded></item><item><title>How interest works: a simple guide</title><link>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-interest-work/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 23:32:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-interest-work/</guid><description>Learn how interest works, including how interest rates affect borrowing and saving.</description><content:encoded>&lt;p>Interest is the extra money paid when borrowing or earned when saving. When you borrow money from a bank, you pay back more than you took. This extra amount is called interest. If you save money in a bank, the bank pays you interest, so you get back more than you deposited. Interest is different from fees and profits. Fees are charges for services, while profits come from owning businesses. Understanding interest helps you know how money grows or costs more.&lt;/p>
</content:encoded></item><item><title>How does inflation work?</title><link>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-inflation-work/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 23:32:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-inflation-work/</guid><description>Learn how inflation works and its effects on buying power and the economy.</description><content:encoded>&lt;p>Inflation is when prices for goods and services rise. This means that money buys less than before. We measure inflation with a number called the consumer price index (CPI). When inflation goes up, people may spend less because they worry about prices rising more. Some reasons for inflation include changes in how much people want to buy and changes in supply. While inflation can cause problems, like making it hard to plan for the future, it can also help the economy by lowering unemployment. Most experts agree that a small, steady amount of inflation is best for the economy.&lt;/p>
</content:encoded></item><item><title>How cash back works with credit cards</title><link>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-cash-back-work/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 23:32:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-cash-back-work/</guid><description>Learn how cash back works with credit cards and how to earn rewards on your purchases.</description><content:encoded>&lt;p>Cash back is a reward you can earn when you use certain credit cards. When you buy something with these cards, you get a small percentage of that money back. This can be in the form of cash or credit on your account. Different cash back cards have different rules. Some give more cash back for certain types of purchases, like groceries or gas. It is important to pay off your credit card balance on time to avoid extra fees. Overall, cash back cards can help you save money on things you need to buy.&lt;/p>
</content:encoded></item><item><title>Understanding how compound interest works</title><link>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-compound-interest-work/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 23:32:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-compound-interest-work/</guid><description>Learn how compound interest works and how it differs from simple interest.</description><content:encoded>&lt;p>Compound interest is the interest added to the original amount of money and the interest that has already been added. This means you earn interest on both your initial money and the interest it has already made. It is different from simple interest, where you only earn interest on the original amount. The way interest is added can change. It can happen yearly, monthly, or even daily. Many banks show how much compound interest you can earn to help you understand your money better. This information helps people compare different financial products.&lt;/p>
</content:encoded></item><item><title>How wi-fi works: understanding wireless internet</title><link>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-wifi-work/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 23:32:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-wifi-work/</guid><description>Learn how Wi-Fi works, including how wireless internet connects devices using radio waves.</description><content:encoded>&lt;p>Wi-Fi is a way for devices to connect to the Internet without wires. It uses radio waves to send and receive data. Many places, like homes and coffee shops, use Wi-Fi to help people connect their devices. Wi-Fi works best when there are no obstacles, like walls, in the way. Different versions of Wi-Fi can send data at different speeds. The range of Wi-Fi can vary, but it usually works well within 20 meters indoors. Wi-Fi helps many devices talk to each other and access the Internet easily.&lt;/p>
</content:encoded></item><item><title>How a secured credit card works</title><link>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-a-secured-credit-card-work/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 23:32:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-a-secured-credit-card-work/</guid><description>Learn how a secured credit card works and how it can help build your credit.</description><content:encoded>&lt;p>A secured credit card is a type of credit card that helps people build or improve their credit. To get one, a person must pay a deposit. This deposit acts as a security for the bank. If the person does not pay their bill, the bank can keep the deposit. Using a secured credit card is similar to using a regular credit card. The cardholder can make purchases and must pay back the money later. This way, secured cards can help users develop good credit habits.&lt;/p>
</content:encoded></item><item><title>How balance transfers work with credit cards</title><link>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-do-balance-transfers-work/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 23:32:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-do-balance-transfers-work/</guid><description>Learn how balance transfers work with credit cards, including benefits and payment methods.</description><content:encoded>&lt;p>A balance transfer is when you move the money you owe on one credit card to another credit card. Many credit card companies want you to do this. They often offer low or no interest rates to make it easier. This can help you save money on interest. When you make payments, they usually go to the lowest interest balance first. You cannot transfer balances between cards from the same bank. The whole process can be done quickly, often in just a few hours.&lt;/p>
</content:encoded></item><item><title>How does a wifi extender work?</title><link>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/wifi-extender-how-does-it-work/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 23:32:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/wifi-extender-how-does-it-work/</guid><description>Learn how a WiFi extender works to improve internet coverage in your home or office.</description><content:encoded>&lt;p>A WiFi extender is a device that helps improve the internet signal in your home or office. It takes the signal from your main router and sends it out again to reach areas that are far away. This makes it easier for devices to connect to the internet. Some extenders can also connect through USB or have an Ethernet port for wired connections. However, the signal from the extender might not be as strong as the one from the main router. Using a WiFi extender can help provide better coverage in places where the internet is weak.&lt;/p>
</content:encoded></item><item><title>How the internet works: basic explanation</title><link>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-the-internet-work/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 23:32:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-the-internet-work/</guid><description>Learn how the Internet works and the basics of its operation, including its impact on communication and information sharing.</description><content:encoded>&lt;p>The Internet is a global system that connects many computer networks. It uses special rules to help devices talk to each other. The Internet includes different types of networks, like those for schools, businesses, and homes. It started in the 1960s for sharing computer resources. Over time, it grew with new technologies and became available to everyone. Today, the Internet offers many services, like email, online shopping, and social media. It has changed how we communicate and get information. There is no single control for the Internet; each part has its own rules.&lt;/p>
</content:encoded></item><item><title>Understanding how apr works on credit cards</title><link>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-apr-work/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 23:32:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-apr-work/</guid><description>Learn how APR works on credit cards and why it is important for understanding interest rates.</description><content:encoded>&lt;p>APR stands for annual percentage rate. It shows how much interest you will pay on a loan or credit card over a year. Lenders must tell you the APR so you can compare different options. There are two types of APR: nominal and effective. The nominal APR is the interest rate multiplied by the number of payments in a year. The effective APR includes fees and gives a more accurate cost of borrowing. Knowing how APR works helps you understand the total cost of using credit cards.&lt;/p>
</content:encoded></item><item><title>How starlink internet works</title><link>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-starlink-work/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 23:32:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-starlink-work/</guid><description>Learn how Starlink internet works using satellites in space for fast and reliable access.</description><content:encoded>&lt;p>Starlink provides internet access using satellites in space. It is a type of satellite internet called broadband. Starlink uses many small satellites in low Earth orbit to send and receive data quickly. This helps people get internet in places where it is hard to reach with wires. Starlink aims to offer fast internet speeds, even in remote areas. The idea of using satellites for internet started a long time ago, but Starlink is one of the most recent projects to make it work well.&lt;/p>
</content:encoded></item><item><title>How a microwave oven works</title><link>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-a-microwave-work/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 23:32:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-a-microwave-work/</guid><description>Learn how a microwave oven works and how it cooks food using microwaves.</description><content:encoded>&lt;p>A microwave oven heats food using electromagnetic waves, which are called microwaves. These waves make water molecules in the food move quickly, creating heat. This process cooks food evenly and quickly. The first microwave oven was made in the 1940s. Over time, they became smaller and cheaper for homes. Today, microwaves are used to heat leftovers and cook many types of food. They are very popular in kitchens worldwide.&lt;/p>
</content:encoded></item><item><title>How does a credit card work?</title><link>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-a-credit-card-work/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 23:31:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-a-credit-card-work/</guid><description>Learn how a credit card works, including how to use it, how payments are made, and how interest is charged.</description><content:encoded>&lt;p>A credit card is a payment card issued by a bank. It allows people to buy things or take out cash on credit. This means the user can spend money they do not have right away, but they must pay it back later. Credit cards can build a balance that may have interest charged. Unlike charge cards, which require payment in full each month, credit cards let users carry a balance. They are different from debit cards, which use money directly from a bank account. Many people around the world use credit cards for payments.&lt;/p>
</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>