<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Money on This Adds Up</title><link>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/categories/money/</link><description>Recent content in Money on This Adds Up</description><generator>Hugo -- 0.147.6</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 23:33:29 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/categories/money/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How student loan interest works</title><link>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-student-loan-interest-work/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 23:33:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-student-loan-interest-work/</guid><description>Learn how student loan interest works, including repayment rules and interest rates in different countries.</description><content:encoded>&lt;p>Student loans help pay for college costs like tuition and books. They usually have lower interest rates than other loans. Some loans let students wait to pay until they finish school. In Australia, a special program called HECS-HELP helps students repay loans based on their income after they graduate. In New Zealand, students do not pay interest while living there. They start paying back loans when they earn above a certain amount. Each country has different rules for student loans.&lt;/p>
</content:encoded></item><item><title>How loan interest works</title><link>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-loan-interest-work/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 23:33:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-loan-interest-work/</guid><description>Learn how loan interest works and how it affects borrowing and saving money.</description><content:encoded>&lt;p>Loan interest is the extra money you pay when you borrow money from a bank. When you take out a loan, you agree to pay back the amount you borrowed plus interest. This interest is usually a percentage of the loan amount. For example, if you borrow $100, you might pay back $110. Interest can also work the other way. When you save money in a bank, you earn interest too. The bank pays you extra money for keeping your savings there. In both cases, interest is a way for banks to make money and for people to earn money on their savings.&lt;/p>
</content:encoded></item><item><title>How a cash advance works on a credit card</title><link>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-a-cash-advance-work-on-a-credit-card/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 23:33:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-a-cash-advance-work-on-a-credit-card/</guid><description>Learn how a cash advance works on a credit card, including costs and repayment.</description><content:encoded>&lt;p>A cash advance on a credit card lets you borrow money using your card. You can take out cash from an ATM or bank. This money is part of your credit limit and you must pay it back. Cash advances often have higher fees and interest rates than regular purchases. It is important to understand these costs before using a cash advance. Make sure you know how much you will owe and when to pay it back.&lt;/p>
</content:encoded></item><item><title>How credit card miles work</title><link>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-miles-work-on-credit-card/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 23:32:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-miles-work-on-credit-card/</guid><description>Learn how credit card miles work and how to earn points with cards like American Express and Chase.</description><content:encoded>&lt;p>Credit card miles are part of loyalty programs that reward you for spending. When you use a credit card for purchases, you earn points or miles. These points can be used for travel, like flights or hotel stays. Different credit cards, like American Express and Chase, have their own ways to earn and use these points. You can also get a loyalty card to track your points. This card may look like a credit card and helps you show that you are part of the program. Knowing how these systems work can help you get more rewards for your spending.&lt;/p>
</content:encoded></item><item><title>How interest works: a simple guide</title><link>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-interest-work/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 23:32:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-interest-work/</guid><description>Learn how interest works, including how interest rates affect borrowing and saving.</description><content:encoded>&lt;p>Interest is the extra money paid when borrowing or earned when saving. When you borrow money from a bank, you pay back more than you took. This extra amount is called interest. If you save money in a bank, the bank pays you interest, so you get back more than you deposited. Interest is different from fees and profits. Fees are charges for services, while profits come from owning businesses. Understanding interest helps you know how money grows or costs more.&lt;/p>
</content:encoded></item><item><title>How does inflation work?</title><link>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-inflation-work/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 23:32:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-inflation-work/</guid><description>Learn how inflation works and its effects on buying power and the economy.</description><content:encoded>&lt;p>Inflation is when prices for goods and services rise. This means that money buys less than before. We measure inflation with a number called the consumer price index (CPI). When inflation goes up, people may spend less because they worry about prices rising more. Some reasons for inflation include changes in how much people want to buy and changes in supply. While inflation can cause problems, like making it hard to plan for the future, it can also help the economy by lowering unemployment. Most experts agree that a small, steady amount of inflation is best for the economy.&lt;/p>
</content:encoded></item><item><title>How cash back works with credit cards</title><link>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-cash-back-work/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 23:32:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-cash-back-work/</guid><description>Learn how cash back works with credit cards and how to earn rewards on your purchases.</description><content:encoded>&lt;p>Cash back is a reward you can earn when you use certain credit cards. When you buy something with these cards, you get a small percentage of that money back. This can be in the form of cash or credit on your account. Different cash back cards have different rules. Some give more cash back for certain types of purchases, like groceries or gas. It is important to pay off your credit card balance on time to avoid extra fees. Overall, cash back cards can help you save money on things you need to buy.&lt;/p>
</content:encoded></item><item><title>Understanding how compound interest works</title><link>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-compound-interest-work/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 23:32:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-compound-interest-work/</guid><description>Learn how compound interest works and how it differs from simple interest.</description><content:encoded>&lt;p>Compound interest is the interest added to the original amount of money and the interest that has already been added. This means you earn interest on both your initial money and the interest it has already made. It is different from simple interest, where you only earn interest on the original amount. The way interest is added can change. It can happen yearly, monthly, or even daily. Many banks show how much compound interest you can earn to help you understand your money better. This information helps people compare different financial products.&lt;/p>
</content:encoded></item><item><title>How a secured credit card works</title><link>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-a-secured-credit-card-work/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 23:32:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-a-secured-credit-card-work/</guid><description>Learn how a secured credit card works and how it can help build your credit.</description><content:encoded>&lt;p>A secured credit card is a type of credit card that helps people build or improve their credit. To get one, a person must pay a deposit. This deposit acts as a security for the bank. If the person does not pay their bill, the bank can keep the deposit. Using a secured credit card is similar to using a regular credit card. The cardholder can make purchases and must pay back the money later. This way, secured cards can help users develop good credit habits.&lt;/p>
</content:encoded></item><item><title>How balance transfers work with credit cards</title><link>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-do-balance-transfers-work/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 23:32:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-do-balance-transfers-work/</guid><description>Learn how balance transfers work with credit cards, including benefits and payment methods.</description><content:encoded>&lt;p>A balance transfer is when you move the money you owe on one credit card to another credit card. Many credit card companies want you to do this. They often offer low or no interest rates to make it easier. This can help you save money on interest. When you make payments, they usually go to the lowest interest balance first. You cannot transfer balances between cards from the same bank. The whole process can be done quickly, often in just a few hours.&lt;/p>
</content:encoded></item><item><title>Understanding how apr works on credit cards</title><link>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-apr-work/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 23:32:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-apr-work/</guid><description>Learn how APR works on credit cards and why it is important for understanding interest rates.</description><content:encoded>&lt;p>APR stands for annual percentage rate. It shows how much interest you will pay on a loan or credit card over a year. Lenders must tell you the APR so you can compare different options. There are two types of APR: nominal and effective. The nominal APR is the interest rate multiplied by the number of payments in a year. The effective APR includes fees and gives a more accurate cost of borrowing. Knowing how APR works helps you understand the total cost of using credit cards.&lt;/p>
</content:encoded></item><item><title>How does a credit card work?</title><link>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-a-credit-card-work/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 23:31:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-a-credit-card-work/</guid><description>Learn how a credit card works, including how to use it, how payments are made, and how interest is charged.</description><content:encoded>&lt;p>A credit card is a payment card issued by a bank. It allows people to buy things or take out cash on credit. This means the user can spend money they do not have right away, but they must pay it back later. Credit cards can build a balance that may have interest charged. Unlike charge cards, which require payment in full each month, credit cards let users carry a balance. They are different from debit cards, which use money directly from a bank account. Many people around the world use credit cards for payments.&lt;/p>
</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>