<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Tech on This Adds Up</title><link>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/categories/tech/</link><description>Recent content in Tech on This Adds Up</description><generator>Hugo -- 0.147.6</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 23:33:40 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/categories/tech/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How 5g home internet works</title><link>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-5g-home-internet-work/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 23:33:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-5g-home-internet-work/</guid><description>Learn how 5G home internet works and its impact on companies like T-Mobile and Verizon.</description><content:encoded>&lt;p>5G is the fifth generation of cellular network technology. It is faster than 4G and can connect more devices at once. 5G has low delays, which helps with real-time communication. This technology can improve services like home internet. Companies like T-Mobile and Verizon offer 5G home internet. They use special antennas to send and receive signals. This allows people to get internet even in crowded areas. Although 5G has many benefits, it also needs a lot of investment to build the networks. 5G is important for new technologies and can help in many fields like healthcare and transportation.&lt;/p>
</content:encoded></item><item><title>What is blockchain in simple words</title><link>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/what-is-blockchain-in-simple-words/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 23:33:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/what-is-blockchain-in-simple-words/</guid><description>Learn what blockchain is in simple words and how it works as a secure digital record-keeping system.</description><content:encoded>&lt;p>Blockchain is a type of digital record-keeping. It stores information in blocks that are connected together in a chain. Each block has a link to the one before it, making it hard to change any information. This system helps keep records safe and secure. Blockchain was first used for Bitcoin, a type of digital money, but it can also be used for other things. Some businesses are looking at private blockchains to keep their data secure. Overall, blockchain is a way to record transactions without needing a central authority.&lt;/p>
</content:encoded></item><item><title>How voip works: a simple guide</title><link>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-voip-work/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 23:33:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-voip-work/</guid><description>Learn how VoIP works to make voice calls over the Internet using simple technology.</description><content:encoded>&lt;p>VoIP stands for Voice over Internet Protocol. It lets people make voice calls using the Internet instead of regular phone lines. VoIP changes voice sounds into data packets that travel over the Internet. You can use special VoIP phones or regular phones with adapters to connect to the Internet. VoIP also works with mobile phones through networks like 4G and 5G. This technology is used in apps like Skype and Google Voice. VoIP calls are similar to traditional phone calls, but they use digital signals and special codes to send sound clearly.&lt;/p>
</content:encoded></item><item><title>How do ip addresses work?</title><link>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-do-ip-addresses-work/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 23:33:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-do-ip-addresses-work/</guid><description>Learn how IP addresses work and their role in internet communication.</description><content:encoded>&lt;p>An IP address is a number that identifies a device on the internet. It helps devices communicate with each other. There are two main types of IP addresses: IPv4 and IPv6. IPv4 is older and uses 32 bits, while IPv6 is newer and uses 128 bits. This allows for many more addresses since the internet has grown so much. IP addresses are managed by a group called IANA and passed to local internet providers. Some addresses are kept for private use and do not appear on the internet.&lt;/p>
</content:encoded></item><item><title>How fiber optic internet works</title><link>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-fiber-optic-internet-work/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 23:33:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-fiber-optic-internet-work/</guid><description>Learn how fiber optic internet works and why it is faster and more reliable than traditional methods.</description><content:encoded>&lt;p>Fiber optic internet sends information using light through thin glass or plastic cables called optical fibers. This method is better than traditional wires for long distances and high speeds. The light carries data like voice, video, and internet signals. Fiber optics have changed how we communicate since they were first developed in the 1970s. They are now commonly used by many internet and phone companies because they are faster and more reliable than older methods. The use of fiber optics has helped improve communication around the world.&lt;/p>
</content:encoded></item><item><title>How portable hotspots work: a simple guide</title><link>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-a-portable-hotspot-work/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 23:32:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-a-portable-hotspot-work/</guid><description>Learn how portable hotspots work and how they provide Internet access using Wi-Fi technology.</description><content:encoded>&lt;p>A portable hotspot is a device that allows you to connect to the Internet using Wi-Fi. It works by using a mobile network to provide Internet access to other devices, like smartphones or laptops. You can set up a portable hotspot on some smartphones or tablets if they have a data plan. Public hotspots are found in places like coffee shops and libraries, allowing many people to access the Internet. Some libraries lend portable hotspots to help people who do not have Internet at home. This helps more people connect to online services.&lt;/p>
</content:encoded></item><item><title>How wi-fi works: understanding wireless internet</title><link>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-wifi-work/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 23:32:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-wifi-work/</guid><description>Learn how Wi-Fi works, including how wireless internet connects devices using radio waves.</description><content:encoded>&lt;p>Wi-Fi is a way for devices to connect to the Internet without wires. It uses radio waves to send and receive data. Many places, like homes and coffee shops, use Wi-Fi to help people connect their devices. Wi-Fi works best when there are no obstacles, like walls, in the way. Different versions of Wi-Fi can send data at different speeds. The range of Wi-Fi can vary, but it usually works well within 20 meters indoors. Wi-Fi helps many devices talk to each other and access the Internet easily.&lt;/p>
</content:encoded></item><item><title>How does a wifi extender work?</title><link>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/wifi-extender-how-does-it-work/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 23:32:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/wifi-extender-how-does-it-work/</guid><description>Learn how a WiFi extender works to improve internet coverage in your home or office.</description><content:encoded>&lt;p>A WiFi extender is a device that helps improve the internet signal in your home or office. It takes the signal from your main router and sends it out again to reach areas that are far away. This makes it easier for devices to connect to the internet. Some extenders can also connect through USB or have an Ethernet port for wired connections. However, the signal from the extender might not be as strong as the one from the main router. Using a WiFi extender can help provide better coverage in places where the internet is weak.&lt;/p>
</content:encoded></item><item><title>How the internet works: basic explanation</title><link>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-the-internet-work/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 23:32:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-the-internet-work/</guid><description>Learn how the Internet works and the basics of its operation, including its impact on communication and information sharing.</description><content:encoded>&lt;p>The Internet is a global system that connects many computer networks. It uses special rules to help devices talk to each other. The Internet includes different types of networks, like those for schools, businesses, and homes. It started in the 1960s for sharing computer resources. Over time, it grew with new technologies and became available to everyone. Today, the Internet offers many services, like email, online shopping, and social media. It has changed how we communicate and get information. There is no single control for the Internet; each part has its own rules.&lt;/p>
</content:encoded></item><item><title>How starlink internet works</title><link>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-starlink-work/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 23:32:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-starlink-work/</guid><description>Learn how Starlink internet works using satellites in space for fast and reliable access.</description><content:encoded>&lt;p>Starlink provides internet access using satellites in space. It is a type of satellite internet called broadband. Starlink uses many small satellites in low Earth orbit to send and receive data quickly. This helps people get internet in places where it is hard to reach with wires. Starlink aims to offer fast internet speeds, even in remote areas. The idea of using satellites for internet started a long time ago, but Starlink is one of the most recent projects to make it work well.&lt;/p>
</content:encoded></item><item><title>How a microwave oven works</title><link>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-a-microwave-work/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 23:32:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://factlessfact.github.io/thisaddsup-site/posts/how-does-a-microwave-work/</guid><description>Learn how a microwave oven works and how it cooks food using microwaves.</description><content:encoded>&lt;p>A microwave oven heats food using electromagnetic waves, which are called microwaves. These waves make water molecules in the food move quickly, creating heat. This process cooks food evenly and quickly. The first microwave oven was made in the 1940s. Over time, they became smaller and cheaper for homes. Today, microwaves are used to heat leftovers and cook many types of food. They are very popular in kitchens worldwide.&lt;/p>
</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>